From 1984 to 1994 a perfect storm of people and
circumstances changed the face of animation forever.
Waking Sleeping Beauty is a documentary film directed by Don Hahn.
By the mid-1980s, the fabled animation studios of
Walt Disney had fallen on hard times.
The artists were polarized between newcomers hungry to innovate
and old timers not yet ready to relinquish control.
These conditions produced a series of box-office flops and pessimistic
forecasts: maybe the best days of animation were over.
Maybe the public didn't care.
Only a miracle or a magic spell could produce a happy ending.
Waking Sleeping Beauty is no fairy tale.
It's the true story of how Disney regained its magic with a staggering output of hits - "Little Mermaid,"
"Beauty and the Beast ," "Aladdin," "The Lion King," and more - over a 10-year period.
Self, played by Don Hahn.
Self, played by Roy Edward Disney.
Self, played by Michael Eisner.
Self, played by Jeffrey Katzenberg.
Self, played by Peter Schneider.
Self - Pumbaa (voice), played by Rob Minkoff.
Waking Sleeping Beauty is a 2009 American documentary film directed by Disney film producer
Don Hahn and produced by Hahn and former Disney executive Peter Schneider.
The film documents the history of Walt Disney Feature Animation from 1984 to 1994,
covering the rise of a period referred to as the Disney Renaissance.
The film uses no new on-camera interviews, instead relying primarily on archival interviews, press kit footage, in-progress and completed footage
from the films being covered, and personal film/videos shot (often against company policy) by the employees of the animation studio.
Waking Sleeping Beauty debuted at the 2009 Telluride Film Festival, and played at film festivals across the country
before its limited theatrical release on March 26, 2010, by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures.
The film explores themes of computer animation, struggle for survival,
documentary filmmaking, innovation, challenge for change.